

Personal details

Name Juan Carlos Ojeda Gomez

Address

Rathmines 96 Upper Dublin, Irland, D06Y684

Phone number +353833270998

Email

juanki.ijcog@gmail.com

Date of birth 01/10/1989

Gender

Male

Nationality Bolivia

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/juank-dev/

Languages

InglesB2EspañolNative

Interests

Infrastructure in cloud Programming

Tecnology

Blockchain

Web3

Juan Carlos Ojeda Gomez

I am a systems engineer who began my career as a full-stack developer after studying at San Simon University. After a few years, I decided to specialize in backend development and gained experience in infrastructure at Mercadolibre as part of the SRE team.

With my newfound knowledge, I transitioned into roles as an SRE and DevOps engineer, focusing on developing and implementing infrastructure solutions to ensure reliability and performance.

Throughout my career, I have been passionate about learning and adapting to new technologies and approaches. My diverse experience has given me a well-rounded perspective and the ability to solve complex problems from various angles.

Work experience

SRE/DevOps Aug 2022 - Feb 2023

Disarmista, Remote in Argentina

As an SRE/DevOps engineer, I had the privilege of working with pagea.cloud as a client with:

- · autoscaling and metrics in Kubernetes
- Clouds: GCP and AWS
- · CI/CD with gitlab
- · Coding with goland, python and bash
- · Metrics with Openseach

SRE/DevOps Aug 2021 - Jul 2022

Bittrap, Remote in Argentina

Responsible for bittrap architecture in aws.

- AWS, EC2, ECR, S3, IAM, Route53, CloudWatch, SQS, SNS, Events, Lambda
- Gitlab CI/CD
- Golang, Bash, Terraform
- Google Workspace Adminitration with GAM Tool and bash scripts
- · Grafana & Prometheus to monitoring
- · Docker Docker, Compose

Site Reliability Engenier

Dec 2018 - Jul 2021

Mercado Libre, Buenos Aires/Argentina

SRE - Troubleshooting Tool to Monitoring VPN, Services, Providers with checks ICMP, HTTP, TCP Full stack Developer and Architecture Designer

- Go(Golang), AWS(IOT, ECS, ECR, IAM, EC2, CloudWatch, SQS, SNS), GCP (Compute Engine), Datadog, NewRelic, Kibana
- · Terraform/Ansible to deploys
- IOT for encrypted communication
- Docker to deploy in almost any place

Platform Security - Discovery PII to Compliance with LGPD

Full stack Developer and Architecture Designer

• GO(Golang), AWS(S3, Macie), GCP (GoogleDLP), Mysql, Object Storage, DocumentSearch

Full Stack Developer

May 2017 - Nov 2018

Government of the City of Buenos Aires, Buenos aires/Argentina

Licenses Department - Maintenance and updating of the licensing system

• Full Stack Developer con PHP, PostgreSQL, Laravel, Docker, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, GO

Full Stack Developer

Apr 2016 - Apr 2017

Baufest, Buenos Aires/Argentina

Cencosud - Sales System Easy Supermarket

• Full Stack Developer PHP, MYSQL, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, HTML

Baufest - Personal Recognition System

• Full Stack Developer Angalar 2, Laravel framework PHP, IONIC.

Full Stack Developer

Jul 2014 - Mar 2016

Freelance, Remote in Bolivia and Argentina

Oceano Virutal Media (España) - Scraping System for Advertising

- Full Stack Developer con PHP, MySQL, C#, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, HTML Bwireless (España) *Proximity Marketing, Social Wifi, Retail Analytics Systems*
- Full Stack Developer PHP, MYSQL, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, HTML

Kitoli (España) - CRM para Laboratorio Fotográfico

• Full Stack Developer PHP, MYSQL, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, HTML

Full Stack Developer

Jan 2013 - Jul 2014

River SRL, Cochabamba/Bolivia

- Desktop Developer C#,SQLServer, Java, MySQL
- Mobile Developer Android con Eclipse
- Web Developer Ruby On Rails, DRUPAL (PHP), Mysql

Education and Qualifications

Bachelor of Systems Engineering

Jan 2008 - Dec 2013

San Simon Major University, Bolivia

B2 Feb 2023

Atlas Languaje School, Dublin, Irland

Skills

AWS
Terraform
Golang
Docker
Bash
SRE/DevOps
Software Architecture
Backend Developer
Monitoring

Courses

AWS Cloud Fundamentals 2019 - 2019

Platzi

Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals

2019 - 2019

Platzi

Professional Software Architecture 2020 - 2020

Platzi

Sep 2022 - Jul 2022

Certificates

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner